<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="/taxonomy/term/46/all" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#">
  <channel>
    <title>Development</title>
    <link>/taxonomy/term/46/all</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
     <atom:link href="/taxonomy/term/46/all/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
    <title>apertus° lance un site dédié à Axiom</title>
    <link>/node/202</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/default/files/field/image/alpha_prototype.jpg&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/field/image/alpha_prototype.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Axiom Alpha&quot; alt=&quot;Axiom Alpha&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bonne année 2012 de la part d&#039;apertus°!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qu&#039;est ce qui pouvait être une meilleure et incroyable fin d&#039;année pour nous que le lancement de notre site pour la future Axiom? Eh bien il y a une chose: le lancement de notre site Web pour la nouvelle Axiom annonçant nos efforts ET le prototype de cette dernière &quot;l&#039;apertus° Axiom Alpha&quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tous les détails sont dans le &lt;a href=&quot;http://axiom.apertus.org/&quot;&gt;nouveau site web&lt;/a&gt; et dans &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:1.7em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://axiom.apertus.org/&quot;&gt; axiom.apertus.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceci signifie aussi malheureusement que - comme certains d&#039;entre vous l&#039;ont déjà deviné - nous ne serons pas en mesure dde faire une levée de fond en 2012. Mais 2013 sera aussi une année apertus° - encore plus que 2012 ne l&#039;a déjà été.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/44&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Axiom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/45&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Axiom Alpha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/46&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/47&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/48&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lens Mount&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/49&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Image Sensor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Alban</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">202 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>apertus° launches Axiom Website</title>
    <link>/node/171</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/default/files/field/image/alpha_prototype.jpg&quot; class=&quot;colorbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/field/image/alpha_prototype.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Axiom Alpha&quot; alt=&quot;Axiom Alpha&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Happy New Year from apertus°!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could be a better ending to an incredible year for us than launching our new Axiom website? Well there is one thing: Launching our new Axiom website AND announcing our Axiom prototype efforts entitled &quot;apertus° Axiom Alpha&quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head on to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://axiom.apertus.org/&quot;&gt;new website&lt;/a&gt; to dive into the details:  &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:1.7em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://axiom.apertus.org/&quot;&gt; axiom.apertus.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unfortunately also means - as some of you might have already guessed - that we will not be able to run crowd funding in 2012. But 2013 will also be a year of apertus° - even more than 2012 already has been.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/44&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Axiom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/45&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Axiom Alpha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/46&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/47&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/48&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Lens Mount&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/49&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Image Sensor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 10:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Sebastian</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">171 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>February 2013 News Update</title>
    <link>/en/node/178</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For February, the shortest month in our calendar, we’re bringing you fresh updates and exciting news regarding what’s taking place with apertus°.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Current state of Axiom Alpha development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our engineering team have been busy working on Axiom Alpha’s Image Processing module, and the Field Programmable Gate Array (short FPGA) for doing the real time image processing of choice now is a recently introduced Xillinx Zynq (FPGA + dual core ARM CPU combination System on Chip [SoC]). We have ordered a Zedboard for prototyping with the Zynq, which is basically like an Arduino with incredible power. It can output a video signal via an onboard HDMI port (unfortunately there is no 3G-SDI option yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zedboard also opens up new possibilities, since its widely available for a reasonable price (much cheaper compared to the price of building custom hardware) FPGA development is easier to split among remotely separated developers - we can just get all of them a Zedboard. And the Zedboard has other interfaces that open up new possibilities that we did not really aim for so far (Gigabit Ethernet, VGA, Audio In/Out, etc.) and will also be used in the final Axiom hardware, so all of the VHDL code that we create now will be reusable later on. Our next step is to create an emulated image sensor in the FPGA that acts like a real one but just generates a test pattern image for now. This is very handy for working on the image processing pipeline without having a real image-sensor front-end built yet. Other team members are working on designing the actual image-sensor front-end hardware in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the skills and want to join our prototype developments here please drop us a line!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The apertus° company has been formed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Here is a big update with good news on the &#039;busy-ness side&#039; of apertus°: The Company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project Founder Oscar Spierenburg has set up the &quot;Apertus Open Source Cinema&quot; company in Antwerp. This company will become the backbone of our future with Axiom and a first step for apertus° to bring open hardware and free software together in a sustainable business plus community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oscar has decided to sign a notary act regarding his and Minske’s film production company &#039;Picoux Productions&#039;. What this means is that apertus° will be officially registered as a branch of the production company, with a clearly defined role for open source camera development and production. In this way, the Axiom camera project can be pushed through the development period with the legal merit of being attached to an offical company. A great benefit of this team up is the reduction of costs (founding costs, book-keeping, etc). Most of the equipment we need for research and development can also now be purchased without losing VAT etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;870&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/BelgiumLawGazette_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BelgiumLawGazette_small.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picoux Production’s accountant will keep an eye on all transactions, ensuring that things are perfectly separated and transparent. He has advised that the apertus° company should be set up as an independent entity (outside of Picoux Productions) once things get bigger. I.e When we have a working prototype, a business plan and a successful crowdfunding campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of all this, Oscar states “I will not take any personal risks with the apertus° branch, nor let it be a risk for the production company. But personally I don&#039;t see any risk in the development period, as long as the spending is not greater than the income. We can, of course, only spend money we gain from sponsors and donations for apertus°. I do believe this solution is the cheapest and safest way to go (for apertus°) and I&#039;m looking forward to it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to help the apertus° Project, donations are very much appreciated. &lt;br /&gt;
You can do this via our &lt;a href=&quot;http://axiom.apertus.org/index.php?site=donate&quot;&gt;official donations page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Vanitas news (referring to Vanitas blog)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Development is underway on Oscar’s feature length film &lt;a href=&quot;http://vanitas.apertus.org/&quot;&gt;‘Vanitas’&lt;/a&gt;. A film shoot took place in Ghent, Belgium earlier this year to create an updated teaser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Vanitas production blog, cast member Manon Verbeeck has written a brief description of the jubilant atmosphere (and bizarre car rides) she has experienced on the project thus far. Be sure to stay tuned to the Vanitas blog for further updates from the cast and crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanitas 2013 Teaser:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;870&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/fqxNNI372ME&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That rounds up our news for this month. But fear not, we’ll be back with more updates soon. In the meantime, if you have any questions, don’t be afraid to join the discussions on our forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/45&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Axiom Alpha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/50&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Vanitas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/47&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/46&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/51&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Organisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 10:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Sebastian</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">170 at </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>February 2013 News Update</title>
    <link>/node/213</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour Février, le mois le plus court dans notre calendrier, nous vous présentons de nouvelles mises à jour et des nouvelles passionnantes sur ce qui se passe avec apertus°.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. L&#039;état actuel de développement d&#039;Axiom Alpha &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Notre équipe d&#039;ingénieurs a été occupée à travailler sur le module du traitement de l&#039;image d&#039;Axiom Alpha, et sur le &quot;Field Programmable Gate Array&quot; (short FPGA) pour le choix du traitement de l&#039;image en temps réel et avec maintenant en plus l&#039;introduction récente de Xillinx Zynq (FPGA + double cœur ARM sur un Chip [SoC]). Nous avons commandé un Zedboard pour l&#039;utilisation avec le Zynq, qui est fondamentalement comme un Arduino mais avec une puissance incroyable. Il peut émettre un signal vidéo via un port HDMI intégré (malheureusement, il n&#039;y a pas d&#039;option 3G-SDI encore).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le Zedboard ouvre également de nouvelles possibilités, et il est largement disponible à un prix raisonnable (beaucoup moins cher par rapport au prix de la construction d&#039;un matériel personnalisé) de développement FPGA est plus facile de diviser les développeurs à distance séparées - nous pouvons simplement obtenir tous un Zedboard. Et le Zedboard a d&#039;autres interfaces qui ouvrent de nouvelles possibilités que nous n&#039;avons pas vraiment viser à ce jour (Gigabit Ethernet, VGA, entrée / sortie audio, etc) et sera également utilisé dans le matériel Axiom finale, de sorte que tous les VHDL Code que nous créons aujourd&#039;hui sera réutilisable par la suite. Notre prochaine étape est de créer un capteur d&#039;image émulé dans le FPGA qui agit comme un vrai mais génère seulement une image du motif de test pour le moment. Ceci est très pratique pour travailler sur le pipeline de traitement d&#039;image sans avoir une image réelle du capteur frontal encore construit. D&#039;autres membres de l&#039;équipe travaillent sur la conception de l&#039;image réelle du capteur frontal du matériel dans l&#039;intervalle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si vous avez les compétences et souhaitez rejoindre nos développements de prototypes ici s&#039;il vous plaît envoyez-nous un message!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. La société ° apertus a été formé&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Voici une grosse mise à jour avec de bonnes nouvelles sur le «affairisme côté» de apertus °: La Société.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fondateur du projet Oscar Spierenburg a mis en place le «Apertus Open Source Cinema&quot; société à Anvers. Cette société deviendra l&#039;épine dorsale de notre avenir avec Axiom et une première étape pour apertus ° d&#039;apporter du matériel et du logiciel libre en même temps dans une entreprise durable ainsi que la communauté.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oscar a décidé de signer un acte notarié au sujet de son et de productions de Picoux &#039;entreprise Minske de la production cinématographique. Ce que cela signifie est que apertus ° sera officiellement enregistrée comme une branche de la société de production, avec un rôle clairement défini pour le développement open source de la caméra et de la production. De cette façon, le projet de caméra Axiom peut être poussé à travers la période de développement avec le fondement juridique d&#039;être attaché à une société officielle. Un grand avantage de cette équipe est la réduction des coûts (coûts fondateurs, comptabilité, etc.) La plupart de l&#039;équipement nécessaire pour la recherche et le développement peuvent désormais être achetés sans perdre de TVA, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;870&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/BelgiumLawGazette_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BelgiumLawGazette_small.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comptable de production Picoux va garder un oeil sur toutes les transactions, veiller à ce que les choses sont parfaitement séparés et transparents. Il a indiqué que le apertus ° compagnie devrait être mis en place en tant qu&#039;entité indépendante (en dehors des Productions Picoux) une fois que les choses deviennent plus gros. C&#039;est à dire Quand nous avons un prototype de travail, un plan d&#039;affaires et une campagne de crowdfunding succès.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;À la lumière de tout cela, les Etats Oscar &quot;Je ne vais pas prendre de risques personnels avec le apertus ° succursale, ni que ce soit un risque pour la société de production. Mais personnellement, je ne vois pas de risque dans la période de développement, aussi longtemps que la dépense n&#039;est pas supérieur au revenu. Nous pouvons, bien sûr, que dépenser de l&#039;argent que nous tirons de sponsors et des dons pour apertus °. Je crois que cette solution est la moins chère et la plus sûre et où aller (apertus °) et je suis impatient d&#039;y être! &quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to help the apertus° Project, donations are very much appreciated. &lt;br /&gt;
You can do this via our &lt;a href=&quot;http://axiom.apertus.org/index.php?site=donate&quot;&gt;official donations page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Vanitas news (referring to Vanitas blog)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Development is underway on Oscar’s feature length film &lt;a href=&quot;http://vanitas.apertus.org/&quot;&gt;‘Vanitas’&lt;/a&gt;. A film shoot took place in Ghent, Belgium earlier this year to create an updated teaser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Vanitas production blog, cast member Manon Verbeeck has written a brief description of the jubilant atmosphere (and bizarre car rides) she has experienced on the project thus far. Be sure to stay tuned to the Vanitas blog for further updates from the cast and crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanitas 2013 Teaser:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;870&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/fqxNNI372ME&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That rounds up our news for this month. But fear not, we’ll be back with more updates soon. In the meantime, if you have any questions, don’t be afraid to join the discussions on our forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/45&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Axiom Alpha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/50&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Vanitas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/47&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/46&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; rel=&quot;dc:subject&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/taxonomy/term/51&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;Organisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 12:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Alban</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">213 at </guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
